Guide to the ILGWU. Permanent exhibit.
ILGWU. Permanent exhibit.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
ILGWU. Permanent exhibit.
5780 Perm exhibit
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
5 linear feet
Memorabilia
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Consists of items that were part of the ILGWU's permanent exhibit in New York City on the history of the union.
ILGWU ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The International Ladies’ Garment Workers’ Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the “new unionism,” the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers’ strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers’ strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the “protocol of peace,” a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Consists of items that were part of the ILGWU's permanent exhibit in New York City on the history of the union.
SUBJECTS
Names:
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; Dodds, Malcolm.; Dubinsky, David, 1892-1982.; Green, Paula.; Humphrey, Hubert H.(Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978.; Kennedy, John F.(John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; McFarlane, Arthur.; Rachelson, Israel.; Rose, Pam E.; Stulberg, Louis, 1901-1977.; Allentown-Easton Health Center --Archives.; Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters' Union --Archives.; American Federation of Labor --Archives.; Cloak and Skirt Makers' Building Association, Inc. --Archives.; Dubinsky Vocational Training School --Archives--Archives.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union --Archives.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 89 (New York, N.Y.)--Archives.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 35 (New York, N.Y.)--Archives.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Joint Board Cloak, Suit, Skirt, and Reefer Makers' Unions--Archives.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 48 (New York, N.Y.)--Archives.; Italian Dressmakers' Union Local 89 --Archives.; McClure's Magazine --Archives.; National Association for Refugee Children --Archives.; New York (State). Electoral College--Archives.; St. Louis Arrangement Committee --Archives.; Sze Keh Vocational School --Archives.; Time Magazine --Archives.; Triangle Shirtwaist Company --Archives.; Union Health Center --Archives.
Subjects:
Labor unions--Collectibles.
Form and Genre Terms:
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more information contact the Kheel Center.
NOTES
"Permanent deposit".
CONTAINER LIST
- Italian Dressmakers' Union Local 89International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 89 (New York, N.Y.), 30th anniversary plaque, 1919-1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Oval bronze plaque with large key attached on top, and lettering "The Spirit of '89". The raised edge has lettering "30th Anniversary - Italian Dressmakers' Union, Local 89 - ILGWU - AFL - 191-1949". The back has the words of "the Spirit of '89" by Pam E Rose; metal-works; 6.5 x 4.5
- McClure's Magazine, bound book, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  McClure's Magazine - vol. XXXVII, May- Oct 1911. Contains articles titled "Fire and the Skyscraper" by Arthur McFarlane; paper (fiber product); book
- Silver bell, from the Cloak, Skirt, and Dress Pressers Union…., 1927 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Silver bell - presented to the Cloak, Skirt, and Dress Pressers Union - Local 35 ILGWU by Israel Rachelson a member of local 35; March 24, 1927; metal-works; bell
- ILGWU - brass key, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Large brass key - commemorating the dedication of the ILGWU - Allentown-Easton Health Center, 1948; metal-works; key
- Louis Stulberg, appreciation plaque (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Plaque of appreciation presented to Louis Stulberg, President of the ILGWU - Service Supreme; wood; metal-works; plaque
- Carved marble stamps; Carved marble stamps - used to stamp the seals of the Sze Keh Vocational School and Dubinsky; marble; stamps, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Encased announcement/endorsement, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Encased announcement/endorsement - "For President of the United States: Hubert H. Humphrey of the State of Minnesota - New York Electoral College 1968 - David Dubinsky - Presidential Elector"; paper (fiber product); plastic; announcement
- Medals issued by President Kennedy, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Medals issued by President John F. Kennedy to commemorate the 50th Anniversary of the First Union Health Center which was created by the ILGWU in 1914; metal-works; medals; 3 in. dia
- Cloak and Skirt Makers', stock certificate, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Certificate of ownership - 1 share of stock in the Cloak and Skirt Makers’ Building Assoc. Inc.; paper (fiber product); certificate; 9.5 x 12.5
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, gold bond, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Gold Bond Certificate issued by the International Ladies Garment Workers Union, valued at $100; paper (fiber product); bond; 9.5 x 12.5
- American Federation of Labor, certificate, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Certificate from the AF of L recognizing one man’s attainment of legal commission and authorization to act as a special organizer for the union; paper (fiber product); certificate; 8.5 x 11
- Silk sash and pin, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Silk sash with "East Side Dress Makers of the L.W. and d.M.U.L. 25" printed on it and a pin with a seal of the Joint Board of the ILGWU displayed on it along with the words "Shop Chairman for Faithful Services rendered 1919"; silk; metal-works; pin (jewelry); sash; pin = 1 cm.; sash=24 in.
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, book of constitution and by-laws, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Small black book entitled "Constitution of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union and By-Laws for Local Unions, 1916"; paper (fiber product); book; 3.5 x 5
- Handbook from the Eleventh Convention of the ILGWU, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Handbook entitled "Report and Proceedings of the Eleventh Convention of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union", needs binding, brittle; paper (fiber product); book
- Book of thanks to David Dubinsky, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  A book of thanks to David Dubinsky for helping establish the Dubinsky Vocational Training School of the National Association for Refugee Children; Chunking, China - Oct. 25, 1945 - also found loose inside the book: a blueprint of the Dubinsky Vocational Training School; correspondence between Dubinsky and the National Assoc. for Refugee Children, Chungking, China; a report on the future plans for the Vocational School in China; paper (fiber product); book
- Dues book from Amalgamated Ladies Garment Cutters Assoc, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Dues book from 1906 for the Amalgamated Ladies Garment Cutters Assoc.; paper (fiber product); book
- Arrangement Committee of the Ladies Garment Workers Union, ribbon (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Ribbon from the Arrangement Committee of the Ladies Garment Workers Union of St. Louis; textiles; ribbon (materials)
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, minutes from the founding meeting, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Meeting minutes from June 3, 1900 founding the ILGWU; paper (fiber product); meeting minutes
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' miscellaneous reports, etc., 1913 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Report of Joint Relief Committee on Aid to Victims of Triangle Fire; Tri-lingual meeting call used to organize white goods and undergarment workers with the ILGWU; Protocol of Peace, Jan. 1913, first collective agreement in the waist and dress industry; envelope designed to celebrate 7th anniv. of ILGWU; a certificate of work issued by the ILGWU; books of ILGWU stamps to fund Anti-Nazism and Anti-Fascism; paper (fiber product); book, envelope, postage stamps
- Dubinsky Seal and Sze Keh Vocational Training School seal, prints (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Prints of the seals/stamps from the Dubinsky and Sze Keh Vocational Training School; paper (fiber products); stamps
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, ribbon, badges., 1911-1971 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Badge/ribbon - "Joint Board Cloak and Skirt Makers Unions - Labor Day 1911"; "Shop Chairman" for the "Cloak and Skirt Makers' Union - ILGWU of New York, Labor Day 1912"; Badges - "Staff", "Press" for the 34th Convention in Miami Beach, Fl., May, 1971"; metal-works; textiles; badges; ribbons (materials)
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, badges, buttons, pins, medals, money clip, 1911-1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Badge - "Guest for the 34th Convention of the ILGWU"; gold color money clip "ILGWU" commemorating the "Golden Jubilee Convention 1900-1950"; Badges - "Delegate" from 34th & 36th Conventions; ILGWU gold plated pins; button - "ILGWU for Dinkins"; metal-works; badges; pins (jewelry); buttons (information artifacts); medals; money clip
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, lighter, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Gold plated lighter "ILGWU, Thirty-Fourth Convention, Miami Beach, May 1971"; metal-works; lighter
- Union Label music/lyrics, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Words and score for the Union Label song, written by Paula Green, music by Malcolm Dodds.; paper (fiber product); song music/lyrics
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union - ticket for opening session of the 40th Anniversary Convention…, and strike ballot from 1932 & 1933, 1932-1940 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Entrance ticket to the Opening Session of the 40th Anniversary Convention of the ILGWU in Madison Square Garden on May 27, 1940. Strike ballot and leaflet encouraging workers to support the strike and join the union in 1932 & 1933; paper (fiber product); ticket; ballot
- Annual Journal - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  "Annual Journal, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, Fifth International Convention, Boston, Massachusetts, Monday, June Sixth, 1904"; paper (fiber product); book
- Newsletter - Out-of-Town Cloakmakers and the War Orphan (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Pages 3-6 of a newsletter (seemingly focusing on Out-of-Town Cloakmakers and the War Orphan Campaign); paper (fiber product)
- Time Magazine Issue, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Time Magazine - August 29, 1949 issue - "Labor's Dubinsky"; paper (fiber product); magazine
- Sealmaker, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. ‡b Local 48 (New York, N.Y.) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Sealmaker for the Italian Cloak, Skirt and Suit-Makers, Local 48 of the ILGWU; metal-works; sealmakers; 10.5 in high
- John F. Kennedy, bust, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Bust/statue (miniature) of John F. Kennedy, a presentation of 65th Anniversary Convention ILGWU, Miami, FL - May 1965; metal-works; statue; 3.5 in dia; 8 in high
- Lithograph slab - ILGWU (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Lithograph stone used to print important documents. Design and wording "International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, Doth Grant This Charter"; See photo in accession folder; cement; 9.5 w x 12.5 l x 2.5 thick
- Lithograph slab - ILGWU (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Lithograph stone used to print important documents. On one side winter scenes, and on the other side the charter used to establish/extend membership to local unions by the ILGWU; cement; 11.5 w x 16 l x 2.5 thick